

Chris Fletcher (Mr) Mobile:(+81) 070-2811-6113 Email: chrisfletcher1989@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/ChrisFletcher1989

Japanese level: JLPT N2

Personal Profile

I am a web-development enthusiast with experience building passion projects in reactJS, Typescript, expressJS and postgreSQL. I firmly believe in the principle of lifelong learning, and I find roles that emphasise results achieved through continuous growth and learning exceptionally motivating. Over the past year, I've immersed myself in the realm of programming, dedicating the majority of my free time to acquiring new skills and tackling personal projects. With a relentless curiosity, I am constantly studying to improve my programming ability, general skills, and to learn new things.

Al Celebrity Recognition Brain React, ExpressJS, PostgreSQL Responsibilities:

- Develop the front and back end at every stage.
- Use react to develop the front-end
- Create the ExpressJS server & postgreSQL database.
- Test, debug and deploy...

Project details:

After logging in, users input an image (url). Al will display the name of the celebrity and how confident it is (fetched via an API).

Tournament Bracket Web-App React, Javascript, CSS

Projects:

Responsibilities: • Consult with dart players

- to decide features.

 Build the entire app independently from
- concept to deployment.
 Create custom algorithms in javascript..
- Custom build the CSS.

Project details:

After entering the number of players, seeds and their names, the DOM renders a tournament grid with players randomly assigned a position + opponent.

Nursery HP & Web-App Typescript, Javascript, CSS Responsibilities:

- Build the entire app from zero independently.
- Consult with the client on their needs.
- Research which weather API to use.
- Develop the full project independently.

Project details:

The client wanted a dynamic HP for their nursery (currently being created). An API displays weather, and subpages let the user learn about the service.

My project previews and source code can be viewed live on my portfolio at: https://chris-fletcher-portfolio.netlify.app/

Technical Skills

Skill		Level
Language /Framework	Javascript	Self Project(s) Completed
	React JS	Self Project(s) Completed
	Typescript	Self Project(s) Completed
	Express JS	Self Project(s) Completed
	Python 3	Proficient
	Node JS	Self Project(s) Completed
	HTML	Self Project(s) Completed
	CSS	Self Project(s) Completed
Database	PostgreSQL	Self Project(s) Completed
Tools	Github	Self Project(s) Completed



Chris Fletcher (Mr) Mobile: (+81) 070-2811-6113

Email: chrisfletcher1989@gmail.com
GitHub: https://github.com/ChrisFletcher1989

Japanese level: JLPT N2

	Postman	Self Project(s) Completed
--	---------	---------------------------

Education

- Higher Education: The University of Hull, BSc Psychology; achieved in June 2010.
- Udemy course: "The complete web-developer in 2023: Zero to mastery" in July 2023.
- FreeCodeCamp course: Responsive Web Design in February 2023.
- Japanese Language Proficiency Test (JLPT): Level 2 in 2023
- IKM Javascript assessment- Proficient result in October 2023

Employment History

Guide Manager: Mimmy inc (Tokyo). June 2021-present

<u>Duties Include:</u> My main role is managing a team of 50 overseas guides for our education platform. The role involves being in charge of recruitment, training, scheduling and general management. I also teach English in this company

English Language teacher: Nova (Tokyo). April 2017-June 2021

<u>Duties Included:</u> Teaching of English materials as a 2nd language. I took a lot of pride in providing the best experience possible for the students and making their goals, my goals.

Founder: Property Photo Geeks Itd (London). September 2015~April 2017

<u>Duties Included:</u> I built this company initially by myself before taking on partners who run it currently. I was in charge of business planning, marketing, sales and product control.

English Teacher: AEON (Tokyo). August 2014-September 2015

<u>Duties Included:</u> Teaching of a variety of English classes as a foreign language. The daily role included group and private adult lessons of all levels as well as all ages of children's classes

Senior Estate Agent: Haart Estate Agents (London). October 2013- August 2014

<u>Duties Included:</u> The role was based around negotiating contracts with those who wish to sell their homes, listening to their requirements and tailoring a plan to their needs. I also was responsible for sales.

Estate Agent: Barnard Marcus (London). May 2012- October 2013

<u>Duties Included</u>: My job was to organise viewings and generate home sales. After negotiating a deal I put in the extra mile to guide it through to completion in a timely manner.

Photographer: Self-employed (London). - September 2010-May 2012

<u>Duties Included</u>: During this time, I researched, planned and began a self-employed business specialising in event photography throughout London.